Hello everyone, I am Mr. Yan, who brings you live broadcast today, and we are going to start a special live broadcast about cloud today.
Before we start, let's take a look at a short video.
We have announced this video in Bilibili, and we have also released it on the public account.
Let's take a look at the video.
In this video, you can see that she is wearing a dress, and she is showing off.
At the beginning, she is wearing a dress like this.
When she walks to the middle of the stage, there will be a movement.
There will be a jacket from her body.
Then it will be sucked into the body of the female model and turn it into a dress.
Then the female model will continue to show off in this dress.
The first theme of this special live broadcast will talk about how we make such a special effect.
Our video has been played.
If you are interested, you can watch it later.
Let's open the cloud.
Then we look for our interface.
Our file has been imported.
Then you can see this is the material we did before.
We click to simulate.
She is a normal 3D fashion.
Then we recorded this kind of clothes.
In this kind of clothing video, we first have to make a special effect of this kind of clothes.
Then how to make it?
We use our editing sewing line tool first.
Choose the clothes we need to make special effects.
Choose their sewing line.
Then we press the right button on the sewing machine and then use our anti-activation sewing line
When our sewing line is anti-activated, it will appear in a white state
At this time, if we click simulate, we can see that the clothes will spread like this
We can pull the 3D window perspective closer
You can see that there are some white lines on it
These are the sewing lines that are anti-activated
If you don't want to see it, you can turn it off in 3D
We can see that there are a lot of pieces of fabric in the clothes
We can still use our sewing tool in the 2D window
Activate the sewing lines of these small pieces of fabric
In this way, it will return to the state of being sewn before
We quickly activate these sewing lines
Because there are so many small pieces of fabric
So we have to slowly activate it
Wait a moment
Ok, we can see that these two pieces of fabric are inside the clothes
Before we do this, we simply press the button on the sewing machine
This is the sewing line
after that, this is the sewing line
To see it, we simply press the button on the sewing machine
If you have any questions, please leave a message at the bottom of the video
Ok, today we will explain how to prank the sewing line
This is a sewing line
As for the sewing line, it is done by
You can see that our clothes will still spread out slowly like just now, but at this time you will find that our small panels are activated and they will not look so fragmented.
Then we can see that under normal simulation, the reason why the clothes are under gravity is that it naturally falls down.
If we want to make a clothes that wants to spread out like this, how should we make it?
Then we need to use the pressure tool that we used to learn how to use the down jacket.
At this time, let's go back to the previous step.
Next, select the top 1 panels in the 2D window.
Then we will change its pressure to 5.
We can change it first.
After changing it to 5, we click on the simulation.
The down jacket will still spread out like this.
When the down jacket is spread out, we can move its perspective to its top.
We can take a look at it.
You will find that its down jacket is now a square.
Because the panel is under pressure, it will spread out from the middle like this.
In this way, our clothes will look more individual.
We can also adjust the different panels to give it different pressure.
You need to try it slowly.
You can try different things.
For example, the size of the clothes, the size of the panels, and some of its particles will be affected.
So we can adjust its pressure differently.
Now I change some of its panels to 1.
At this time, let's simulate it again.
You can see that its speed is a little slower than just now.
Because it is under a little pressure.
You will find that some of its panels spread out faster than others.
Some of its panels spread out slower than others.
That's because our clothes are attached to people.
The friction of the human body is different.
So some of its panels will also be under pressure.
It will be different.
If we want to limit the shape of the clothes, you can give it a shape simulation.
After adjusting the clothes, we come to the animation mode.
When you are in animation mode, click the recording in the lower left corner.
You can move the clothes from a complete cloth to one.
Then you look at the activate motion by slowly moving from a complete cloth to another.
Let's record the motion.
Then you can move the clothes from a complete cloth to another.
Okay, then we can record it.
After the recording is completed, we select the video we recorded earlier and record it.
You can see that we recorded this action.
After that, we will get a small video like this.
We can put it aside for a while.
You can see that it is a process of disassembling the clothing.
We can adjust it with a mouse and then put it in a simple way.
You can see that we can find that it is made up of pieces like this.
And then it slowly forms a whole piece of clothing.
After we get this video, we can save it.
Then use the third-party editing software to make it.
We can see that there is a model in the video.
Rotating and falling.
How do we make this?
We need to select our video capture.
Then find our rotation recording.
After we click on the rotation recording, we first adjust our video size.
Then you go to adjust a time.
After adjusting the time, we first click on the 3D clothing rotation video.
Then click on the video in the lower left corner.
Then it will record it at the same time.
This action of rotating the clothing while spreading.
This action is very important.
After we finish recording this action, we will play a video frame like this.
We first play a video frame.
You can see that it is a video that spreads like this.
We can check the playback process by manually adjusting it.
Then we can see that these clothes will slowly rotate through the model from a piece of metal.
Then it can be absorbed into the model.
Form it into a whole piece of clothing like this.
And slowly rotate to a state of a complete body.
After we get this video, we can save it.
Then use a third-party video editing software.
Then you can edit this section.
You can see that it is very easy to edit.
Is it cool?
The method is also very simple.
If you have time, you can try it.
Okay, then we will start another special live broadcast.
It is about the production of wind and such heavy-duty effects.
Let's open a new 3D file.
You can see that there is such a gathering at the 3D window.
This gathering has been adjusted to a model before.
I changed the posture of the model to an action that took off.
Then we'll use this cloth to show you the wind control system and the heavy-duty effect of the model.
If I want to make a skirt that looks like it's blown up by the wind,
how can I do that?
We can find a wind control device in the lower left corner of the 3D window.
Find the wind control device under the 3D skirt.
After opening it, there will be a triangle here.
This triangle is our wind control device.
We click on the simulation and then select our wind control device.
On the right side, we can find the activator.
After we click on the activator,
our clothes will be blown up by the wind.
It will move like the wind is blowing.
We will find that the direction of the triangle point is the direction of the wind.
There are two types of wind.
We will introduce them separately later.
First, let's take a look at the effect of moving the triangle.
For example, we move the triangle to the middle.
You will find that the position of the skirt that it points to is different,
and the direction in which the clothing is blown will also be different.
Next, we will change the type to a ball.
The ball is blown around with the wind control device as the base.
The area of the wind will be larger.
There is also a adjustment about the strength of the wind.
We can see that on the right side,
for example, we will reduce the strength.
The smaller the value, the smaller the wind strength.
The larger the value, the greater the strength.
You can see that.
Then,
we will adjust it.
For example, we need to adjust it slowly,
because the impact of our fabric will also be greater.
We can see that there are some other parameters below.
For example, the symbol value is 0 to 100.
The symbol value is the distance range of the wind effect.
According to the set value,
the wind will be reduced in the form of a wave line.
If it is 0, it means that the wind is blowing at an infinite straight line.
If there is a value,
the wind will blow out in the form of a wave line.
You can try it.
Then below,
there will be a frequency below the symbol value.
Its unit is seconds.
The frequency is a frequency of the set wind.
According to the set of a second,
the wind will repeatedly increase and decrease.
The value is connected,
which means that there is no frequency.
It maintains a constant speed of blowing wind.
This is the effect of frequency.
Then below,
for example,
I now change it to a 3.
I change it to a 0.
Next is about the airflow.
The airflow is the irregular blowing of the set wind.
The higher the value,
the more irregular it is blown.
Now,
through the adjustment of these values,
we blow our clothes to a more suitable state,
the shape you need.
Are you looking for a small CG?
If you look at this,
you will find that if we turn on the wind,
then you can see the skirt.
It will return to its original state due to gravity.
If I want it to be blown,
how can I keep it in this state?
We can use our simulation attribute directly.
Click on the right to find the simulation attribute here.
On the right side, we can see that there is a gravity, and we can change the default value of 9800 to 0.
At this time, we will activate the wind again.
After we activate the wind, our clothes are blown up again.
At this time, we can pull the clothes.
After we pull the clothes, we select the wind control device again and turn off the wind.
After turning off the wind, you will find that our clothes will not fall quickly,
because the gravity of the 3D window is 0.
You will find that the clothes will still change slowly.
If I want to restrict the clothes to such a dynamic, what should I do?
We can open the simulation element.
There is an air resistance here.
We will increase the resistance of the air.
The greater the resistance of the air, the more we can maintain the clothes in the 3D space.
This is the state of the clothes.
You can see that the clothes will move very slowly.
Well, have you learned it?
It's very simple.
We use wind, gravity, and air resistance to complete such a small creative performance.
We can adjust the clothes.
It's very easy to adjust the shape of the clothes.
Next, let's open another file.
Let's continue to use the effect of wind and gravity.
We can see that the model that came in today is also in a state of flying.
For example, this model is flying.
I want to show the effect of wind blowing on the panel below.
Next, I will open my wind control device on the left.
After using it, we will activate the wind control device.
After activation, our panel will be blown up like this.
You will find that.
Then we will activate it again.
Ok, the panel above.
I will activate it back now.
This will reduce the amount of calculation.
Now we are going to keep activating the wind control.
We can move the view to its back.
Because the wind is an axis,
it blows a wind.
So we change its wind shape to the earth.
In this way, we can get a separation wind.
This way, the amount of the dress will be larger.
Now let's turn off the wind and open the window to adjust the shape of the skirt.
Let's change the gravity to 0 and the air resistance to 30.
Now let's adjust the shape of the skirt manually.
Now let's adjust the shape of the skirt manually with the hand-grabbing tool.
Now the skirt is very beautiful.
At this time, we can create a new version of the skirt.
We can create a new version of the skirt by using the missing environment.
Now let's move the skirt to the right position.
Please wait a moment.
We need to adjust it slowly.
At this time, we can open the model and move the skirt manually with the hand.
We can see that the skirt is floating.
Let's adjust the shape of the skirt to the shape we want.
After we have adjusted this form, we will go to the next step, which is to create a new
model.
After we have adjusted this form, we will enter the rendering window to render the current
image.
After we click on the actual rendering, we can see the state of our clothing after rendering
on the right.
You can see that this form plus this matching is still relatively beautiful.
Now, I have used a metal surface for the model.
We can see that the model has been rendered.
Now, I can adjust the background of the model's 3D rendering window to make it a little darker.
Then we can see that its default light is 1.
Its original light is default 1.
Then we reduce its value.
In this way, our overall picture will look darker.
Then we can add a vertical light to give it such a top light.
You can see that.
It looks like this.
This top light will be according to a certain design.
This warning light, we can edit it.
Its concentration can then beMastered to Allah, to increase the brightness of the lights,
and then we can edit the color of one of its warning lights.
We are different colors Is it?
which is separate will be the that we can see at the same time we can change the width
of a warning light a little.
For example.
This will make the lamp bigger and the light on the model will be more.
We can also adjust the position of the 3D space,
so that the light will not be so strong and the light will be weaker.
We can also add a giant lamp like this,
so that we can add a light at the bottom of the skirt.
Because the bottom of the skirt is darker now.
We can also adjust the light at the bottom of the skirt.
For example, we can adjust the color of the skirt.
Different colors are different on the model.
And the light is different on the model.
The intensity of the light can be adjusted.
If we don't want to see the light,
we can turn off the display of the giant lamp.
In this way, the light will not appear from the actual rendering.
This is the light version of the lamp.
We can also use some of the rendering we talked about before.
For example, we can set the surface of the panel
to be this one.
We can also select the panel of the model's front chest,
change its back side to be a light.
At the same time, we can change the color of the panel.
Let's render it.
You can see that the panel used for this fabric
has some blue light on its back side.
such as blue and light.
We can also adjust the color of the panel.
We select the material and adjust the color of the material.
We can make changes.
And there is a color intensity below.
The higher the intensity, the higher the degree of light.
At the same time, we can also adjust the side of the fabric according to this attribute.
For example, I will also change the side of the side to light rendering.
Then adjust a color for it.
In order to make a good distinction, I will change the color to a purple like this.
You can see that it is more obvious.
I will increase the intensity of its color a little bit.
Then run the rendering.
You can see that there is a little bit of purple light on the edge of the panel.
Then we can use the rendering attribute of the fabric to change its attributes.
In this way, we can render some different creative pictures.
We can make some different scenes through the characteristics of this panel.
For example, I will create a new file.
This is the round-shaped panel that we have prepared.
You can see that after the panel is inserted, it is a normal round shape.
But the difference is that I applied a light attribute to the side of the fabric.
And I have adjusted its color and color intensity.
Now I am rendering the panel.
After rendering, we can see that the side of the panel is shining with blue light.
If I choose the front of the fabric, I will change its front transparency to 0.
Then we can see that the panel will have the effect of a circle of blue light.
We can use this setting to make some designs for our panel.
For example, I will make a hole in it.
In this way, we can get a double-layer light.
OK.
Then we can adjust its transparency.
Let's take a look.
You can see that there is a hole in the middle of the panel.
We will render the panel that we have just set.
You can also make some scenes according to the characteristics of the panel.
I can insert a finished panel scene here.
This is a finished panel scene.
It is also a very simple round effect of a panel.
You can also try to make some glowing eyes with this.
OK.
Let's adjust the position of this panel.
At this time, we will click on the rendering.
Let's do an actual rendering to see its effect.
You can see that the model body around the panel has a light effect.
Then we will adjust the background color to darken it a little bit.
It will be more obvious.
You can see that it is still very cool.
Right?
OK.
Next, I can use different panels to create different scenes.
For example, I've just built a bigger panel.
I want to create a mirror effect for it.
We can use the panel to create it.
Let's create a new panel first.
Let's move the panel to the corresponding position.
Let's turn on the other clothes to reduce the calculation.
Let's adjust the position of the panel.
When we want to create a mirror effect,
remember to change the material property to the material for the model.
Remember to change the material property to the material for the model.
So it can reflect our model's shadow.
Let's adjust the version a little bit more.
Click on the rendering to see if the current adjustment position is appropriate.
We can see that this version is a little far from our model,
so it is a light version and does not reflect our model.
Let's change the angle and adjust it a little bit.
For this kind of general adjustment and rendering,
we will have a burning smell of CPU on this computer.
We can see that the current version is a little far from our model,
so it is a light version and does not reflect our model.
Click on the rendering to see if the current adjustment position is appropriate.
We can see that this version is a little far from our model,
so it is a light version and does not reflect our model.
The rendering window will start to render in real time,
and let's adjust its position again.
delete the floating sand
Let's change the color of the panel to a darker blue.
As you can see, the 3D rendering window is now rendering.
You can see the overall effect.
We can also add some other lights.
For example, the sphere lamp.
Adjust the size of the sphere lamp.
Adjust the intensity of the sphere lamp.
Adjust the state of the rendering.
This is the rendering of this scene.
Next, we will add another package.
We will make some other scenes.
We can adjust the settings.
You can find the angles you prefer.
We will make some high-intensity rendering.
We will open a new project file.
We can see that this model is a virtual model that we have previously foretold.
It has a hand movement like this.
We will show it.
You will find that it is now a default light.
In this place, we mainly talk about the characteristics of a big light, such as a big top light, a positive light and a big reverse light.
First of all, we will reduce the intensity of this light line.
Reduce the intensity of its default round light.
Then we will show it.
Then we will add a top light to it to check it out.
You can see that I am using a glass material for this model.
Now I will move this top light to the bottom of its foot.
Make a bottom light like this.
The effect of lighting up from the bottom.
My CPU has started to burn.
I am going to do this now.
Adjust the width and height of the light.
And change its color.
Now we will adjust the intensity of the light to 0.
You can see that you now have a scene like this.
We can turn off the next virtual light.
Then we will add a round light to it.
Let's add a round light like this.
Let's change the radius.
I see that there are friends who ask you are there any other materials at the model's dress?
For the dress, we just see that the top and bottom used are just the usual silk materials.
The material of the silk and these pieces on the body,
we just talked about it,
that is, we set this fabric to a reverse light like this.
Let's adjust it a little bit,
add a little bit of light to it.
For this light,
we are going to adjust it slowly,
to reach a better state slowly.
We don't have a shortcut key for lighting.
Then we find a sphere lamp that we have added before,
and modify the color of this sphere lamp.
Then we can see that it is now a slightly blue light.
Then I will make it a backlight effect like this.
We add a new sphere lamp,
arrange this sphere lamp behind the model,
and adjust the size of the sphere lamp.
Generally, this sphere lamp will be adjusted very large.
We push this light back a little bit.
Our material is a very simple board.
You can try it yourself.
After adjusting this light,
we set a color for it.
We turn off its display.
At this time,
you can see that there is a light blue circle around the model body.
This is because of the backlight effect.
It has a sense of backlight.
Then we can adjust the original light intensity to zero.
You can see that the model body will emit a blue light three times.
That's because we added such a backlight effect to it.
The backlight effect is like this.
Let's adjust the intensity of the different light.
Let's see the change of its light.
Let's rotate this model and show you.
The back of this model has a relatively large area of light.
It is a blue light like this.
Because its body is blocked,
it only has some light around its body.
I chose a glass material for this model.
It is a gemstone material.
If your clothing feels too dark in front,
we can add a giant light to it in front of the clothing.
You can see that the front of the clothing will not be so dark.
I don't recommend you to adjust the backlight intensity too high.
Because if the exposure is too high,
there will be no effect.
We need to adjust it slowly.
Of course, you can also adjust the angle of the model.
Check out its different light effects.
And adjust the height of our light.
Because this model is relatively high.
Adjust the height of the model.
In this way, the light received will be more even.
You can see that the effect is better.
Next, let's download a new file.
In this way,
I will show you how to create some environment with the file.
To achieve some cool effects.
Let's add this model.
In fact, this style is still the same style.
I just made some minor adjustments.
You can see that I have adjusted this clothing.
Under the model,
why does the white clothing have blue light?
Because I added it before.
I added a blue background.
We can turn on the light to show you.
There will be a very large blue light board under its feet.
It will make the model look like this.
You can see it.
Next, let's download a scene that has been made in advance.
This scene is very simple to make.
We just used a few large boards to make it.
We can show you its effect first.
Let's take a look at its effect.
You can see that this board.
I applied this metal material to it before and after it.
The side applied a light material to it.
If you feel that the side of the light is not obvious during the production process,
you can adjust the thickness of this rendering.
Adjust it a little thicker.
We can adjust its perspective to the top right.
You can see that I made this scene.
It's still relatively large.
There are a few very large boards.
It's a scene like this.
During the rendering process,
you can smell the scent of the CPU.
Next, let's add some other small lights to it.
For example, I like to add some moon effects to it.
For example, I'll add a circular light to it.
Here is the sphere light.
This sphere light is not bad.
It's still a shiny sphere light.
I'll make its perspective a little bigger.
We can also add a light to the front of the costume.
The front of the costume is still a little dark.
Today's live stream is always in a mode of taking off.
The live stream is always in a mode of taking off.
It has been flying all the way down.
I'll hide the light board for now
and adjust the intensity of its light.
adjust the intensity of its light.
Now we can see that this model
Although its Leg has a small piece
Its feet has two small wings.
there will be a mirror effect at the foot of the model, right?
Because I added a metal layer at the bottom.
Next, I'll add a scene like this.
We can add a scene to check it out.
Because I have a color background now,
I'll make it simple with this color.
This way, our scene will be displayed.
As you can see, after adding a background image like this,
we get this effect.
Does it look like your WeChat account?
Actually, we have many parameters that we need to adjust and check by ourselves.
We can rotate the overall scene at the 3D window to check its effect.
Why doesn't the background image move?
Because the background image is just a picture.
You can use these panels to build different scenarios to achieve your special effects.
Next, let's look at a project file that we shared before.
How is it made?
It's a support file.
It's a support file. It's a support file. It's a support file. It's a support file.
It has a little bit of a shredder effect in it.
You probably saw this picture in public.
I made these shredders with blocks.
Very simple.
As long as you draw a square and cut it into pieces.
And I've placed a metal surface in a square.
As for the sides, they are made of a shiny material.
We can see that they are all very simple methods.
In this case,
Click on the rendering and change the size of the rendering.
You can see that this is the rendering we have shared before.
For the background, we use a background.
For example, I delete the background.
We can see the effect.
Change the background to black.
Then we can import some other background pictures to see the different effects.
You can see that this is a background effect.
You can see that this is a background picture.
Then we can import some other background pictures to see the different effects.
Then we can adjust the different colors to show the effect of the test.
Okay, after this material is shown, our live broadcast today will be a special live broadcast, and it will end here.
If you have any questions, we can leave a message to the teacher on this bar.
I will help the teacher to help you answer them one by one.
Okay, let me see if everyone has any questions.
Are these pieces drawn one by one?
This piece is very easy to make.
Okay, let me see if everyone has any questions.
You draw a larger sheet, and then you put a lot of these inner lines in it, and then you divide these pieces into a segment.
You can see that in today's live broadcast file, we have talked about this feature.
This feature is mentioned, and someone is praising me.
This voice is very cute.
Hahaha, you can see this scene, the light circle we talked about, and the background, which are some of the production methods we just talked about.
It's very simple.
They are all used to make sheets.
Add a side light to the side of the board.
And then this is what we just talked about.
It's a special effect of glass shavings.
There will be a replay.
We will play the content of today's live broadcast in a week.
Someone asked about the high-quality rendering of 3D windows.
The model is very dark when opened.
Did you turn off the lighting of the 3D window?
You can find the 3D environment lighting in the 3D hammer and hammer bar on the left.
Then check it out.
The 3D world is unaaS.
TianaBat Blair для您
For shading a picture in 3D window,
it is necessary to zoom in for the effect.
The ανα
I don't know what you're talking about, which is the corresponding shadow, which is the model, the projection of the model, that is, you are under the model, you can set it to a metal board like this under the foot.
Can you make videos like VR rotation?
What about the background?
I hope you can put it in the future.
You can dare to try it.
The effects of the walk show?
The effects of the walk show, the teacher is using the cloud recording, then using the third-party editing to simply cut it for him.
If you only have a mirror piece, if you let the piece move, you can use other software, you can set it, you can, but you have a good idea, you can make some pieces in the three-dimensional window, and then use the rotation recording to turn this piece around.
I guess it's also very cool, you can try it.
In the later stages, you can use editing software, you can use any editing software, such as PR, AE, or you can edit your mobile phone.
Three days, three days is a bit difficult.
Some people ask how to do the symmetry effect just now, is it played in the video?
The effect of playing in the video, I recorded it in our software, recorded two different directions of the walk show, and then cut it together.
I was like, ah, I'll try it again, and then it will be a little bit better.
Then I was like, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
The symmetry effect is, I use the board.
Some students ask, how do you do the symmetry effect?
We use our board, use the board to set a metal material for him.
If you do this, he can be projected.
How to do this, you can use it, you can use it, you can use it.
hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello hello
Hello hello?
Can I work?
You can pay attention to the official website,
You can look forward to the live stream next Friday.
The teacher is very clear about it.
The teacher has already laughed.
Let me show you some other special effects.
This is another scene of my rendering.
As you can see, I used a board to make a bucket.
I set up a glass material for this bucket.
As you can see.
Some of you asked me how to do the reflection.
I used a metal material for the blue part.
Adjust the color of the board and you can do the reflection.
Can I eat the food that the teacher made?
It's a bit difficult.
Thank you.
I feel like the teacher is very young.
Guess how old I am.
I should be coughing while teaching.
That's what you expect, right?
Don't expect me to get younger by watching me eat the food.
I didn't.
Well, you did.
Thanks.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
大家还有问题没有大家还有问题没有我们的直播还有八分钟就要结束了大家可以看一下这张图给大家看这张图的目的呢就是大家可以尝试一下像这个呢是一张摄影作品那我们可以用其实也可以用我们的软件的去给我们的模特去做一些这样的特效都是我们刚才讲过的一些功能
包括像这个也是大家可以去尝试
对这个这个对称就是用版片做的呀看来你没有好好听课你肯定在下面给小C君在在车
下次要好好听好好听课这个就是我刚才重复了很多遍就是用版片做的
这个来迟了的是刚来吗
你是不是来的有点早
大家还有什么问题没有
我们下次的直播是关于我们的一个纹理处理的一个课啊也是干货非常的多
大家一定要到时候准点到啊不要进像今天一样
开始了才进来
对还有结束了才进来的
农务的效果可以
呃农务的效果你可以发挥你的想象啊比如说像老师刚才讲过的这个失重的效果你可以用一些沙的板用一些板片做一些沙
然后呢将这个板片漂浮在空中然后呢给他调一些这种雾面的效果
说不定你就可以渲染出来这个农务的效果
我们期待你的投稿
嗯